instantposition.com 2009-04-03

# Instant Position Privacy Policy

## Members and General Public 

Instant Position has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm and continuing commitment to the privacy of personal information provided by those visiting and interacting with Instant Position. We hold the privacy of your personal information in the highest regard. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.

### Website Usage Information

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. We use cookies to identify members and allow them access to member only areas of our Web site. We use tracking information to determine which areas our site users visit based on traffic to those areas. Instant Position does not track what individual users read, but rather how often each page is visited. This helps us maintain a superior and informative website for you.

The Information We Collect  
Our registration forms require users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, format preference (HTML vs. Text), address, and facts about your company size, database type, and similar information. We do not request sensitive information from our visitors, such as credit card or social security numbers for member signups or contact forms. When collecting ordering information, we use the latest SSL technology for your security. We use customer contact information from the registration forms to send the user requested information about our company. We never sell, share or trade any of our customer information with other companies. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen.

Links  
This site contains links to other sites. Instant Position is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of these sites and determine if that site protects your privacy in a responsible manner and to your satisfaction.

Security  
Instant Position has made a substantial investment in the latest servers, database, backup and firewall technologies to protect our information assets. These technologies are deployed as part of sophisticated security architecture. All data resides in a tightly controlled, secure data center. These investments mean that information about the identity and preferences of individual members is never accessible to anyone outside Instant Position. We will maintain safeguards to protect the security of these servers and your personally identifiable information.

Marketing Newsletter   
When you signup for a membership, we will use the email address and format preference you provide to send you updates on SEO Tools and related facts, notification of new SEO Tools, events, and strategies to make your marketing campaign a success. You may remove your name from this list at any time by logging into your member area and changing your preference.

Surveys  
We may conduct occasional online surveys via our website or via an email newsletter. These surveys are entirely voluntary and you may easily decline to participate. Participating in an online survey does not automatically add your name to the subscriber list for the Instant Position. You are always given the opportunity to choose what information you want to receive.

Acquisition or Changes in Ownership of Instant Position,   
In the event that Instant Position, (or a substantial portion of its assets) is acquired, customer information would be considered part of those assets, and may be part of those assets that are transferred.

Policy Modifications  
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when Instant Position makes changes to this privacy statement, we will email users who have given us permission to do so. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, without your prior consent.

Contacting Instant Position about Privacy and Instant Position.com  
If you have any questions about our privacy statement, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact: [customersupport@instantposition.com](mailto:customersupport@instantposition.com?subject=Instant%20Position%20Privacy%20Inquiry)
